It's so nice and cool in the shade.
Izumi!
Get over here!
We gotta decide where we're
goin' over summer break.
Right, it's summer.
Upsy-daisy...
Coming!
Ow!
Some things never change.
At this point, I hardly think anything of it.
It really is summer...
It's so hot.
And the sun's particularly bright today.
Zero
Resistance
to the Sun
Whoa, cold! Wh-What...?
For you.
Shikimori's Not Just a Cutie
Shikimori's
Not
Just
a
Cutie
Shikimori's
Not
Just
a
Cutie
Shikimori's
Not Just a Cutie
Amusement Park
Shikimori-san might like it??
Get a reservation!!!
Get gifts for the family
Eat this!!
Keep warm and go to bed early!!
Inuzuka-kun!!
Please Help
I'm going to an amusement park with
Shikimori-san next week. Suggestions...?
Inuzuka-kun
#04  How They Each Feel at the Start of Summer
Did I startle you?
Thanks, Shikimori-san.
Make sure you stay hydrated, Izumi-san.
She's dazzling!
Like a model in a commercial!
You can get under my parasol.
Thanks.
Thanks, Hachimitsu.
You sure about this?
Well, it's just Hachimitsu.
I'll hold it, Hachimitsu-san.
How thoughtful of you, Izumi.
I know! I wanna go to the
beach over summer break!
What?!
The beach?!
She sure is excited.
I guess Shikimori-san really likes summer.
Into Culture
Into Athletics
The beach is awesome!
Nothing says summer like the beach, right?
Summer ✕
Winter 〇
Uh-huh! Uh-huh!
Summer 〇
Winter ✕
The beach, huh? It does sound fun...
But I always burn instantly and
make things harder for everyone else,
so I just end up sitting
in the shade watching.
Wait, wouldn't the river be better?
Izumi likes cooler places more, right?
He's sensitive to the sun,
but we can still swim at the river.
Oh, man! The river sounds great, too!
H-Hang on...
If you want to go to the beach,
don't hold back on my account.
We're not holding back.
We're discussing this because we want
to go somewhere we can all enjoy.
Yeah, exactly!
What's your pick, Izumi?
I-I think...
I'd also... like to go to the river.
It's settled, then!
Izumi and the river still sounds like
a dangerous combination, though.
Gulp!
G-Good point...
It'll be fine.
I'll be there.
You're so cool, Micchon!
Too cool! The coolest!
C-Come on... You're gonna make me mad!
You're embarrassed! How cute!
Hey!
You're all red!
You okay with the river, Hachimitsu?
I am not!
I want to lounge around at someone's
house with the AC blasting.
Hey!
Spending all summer break
lounging around at home is just...
That's a good idea, too!
Let's do it all!
I think anything would be fine.
Oh, I wanna go to a festival!
This summer...
might just be...
the best I've ever had.
A Few Days Later
Final Exam Week
Finals week kicks off today!
That means all clubs are on break!
Y-You sound happy.
Of course I am!
Because the best way to spend
the first day of summer is...
Going shopping for our river trip!
What gives? We came 'cause
you said we were gonna study!
What do you even want to buy?
Let's go home.
Yeah, we already have all the
stuff we need for a barbecue.
You don't get it at all.
You are so clueless...
You're totally thinking up
something now, aren't you?
If we're going to the river,
we need swimsuits!
True.
Totally On Board
Uh, only little kids wear
swimsuits at the river.
You're no help at all today!
Well, we're all in trouble if we don't study!
You're more serious than
your face suggests.
My face is serious, too!
Will you be swimming, Izumi-san?
Oh, me? Hmm...
Zero Resistance to the Sun
Sunburned All Over
You poor, poor thing.
Nah, I think I'll pass.
So you won't be wearing a swimsuit?
Why do you ask?
No reason.
I was just thinking that's a shame.
Huh?
Wait, wh-what does that mean?!
It feels like Izumi's always right
in the palm of Micchon's hand.
Sometimes her "Teasermori" side comes out.
Come shop swimsuits with us, Micchon!
If Izumi-san won't be swimming,
I don't need one.
Boo.
Well, we're gonna go look.
Whoo-hoo.
Those two really just do their own thing...
What should the three of us do?
Those abs sure are something...
That's so cool...
I... I...
Shikimori-san?
I'm going to the restroom!
Huh?
The restrooms are the other
way, Shikimori-san!
You and I might as well go
to the food court and study.
Th-This is...
It's the one from that ad.
Hey, Micchon! You're here, too?
Check it out!
Isn't this swimsuit wild?!
What's with the frills?
Don't hold it up to me.
Y-You can't go with that one, Micchon!
W-Wait, this isn't...
It's not what it looks like, I swear!
I-I-Izumi-san was looking at an ad
with this swimsuit in it earlier!
I figured he must like this kind of thing...
So I was just looking!
That's all! I wouldn't...
Ah! So that ticked you off, huh?
Just a little bit.
I hear ya.
Must be rough.
You do hate losing, after all.
Huh?
You didn't realize?
I guess you wouldn't, huh?
Huh? What?
It doesn't usually show,
but it creeps up every now and then.
Like right now.
Hey, Hachimitsu...
What?
Isn't Shikimori, like... super cute?
Who's Shikimori again?
She's in our class!
Remember your own classmates!
That small face, that silky hair...
She's slender, she's smart,
she has big eyes and long eyelashes...
And on top of all that, she's super nice!
She tops the list of girls
you'd want to marry!
She's a classic Japanese beauty!
She's way too freakin' graceful!
I wanna be her friend!
Chill out. You're being creepy.
Everyone gets creepy when there's
a cute girl in front of them.
I just wanna be friends with her.
I mean, I get it.
When you're dealing with
someone that perfect,
it's hard to know where to start.
Exactly! And on top of that...
I heard she and that Izumi guy
just started dating!
When they're together, the air around
them is just so pure! It's freaky!
You have a point.
Still, you really adore girls like that, huh?
"Girls Like That"
Simple and Clean Maidens
I mean, I'd love to be like that.
I'm too tall, and I'm pretty tactless, too.
Not like that bothers me or anything, but...
Girls who are soft and airy and smell nice...
Ones who make you want to protect them
just catch my eye so easily!
They're my polar opposite!
What I'm saying is...
Shikimori is my ideal woman!
Is she?
Yes, she is!
Gather 'round, girls!
We're starting your basketball game!
Hurry up!
All right, game time! I can't wait!
Let's go!
It's just part of class.
Don't take it seriously.
I know that!
I can tell the difference between
playing for real and for fun.
I'm not so sure.
Maybe I'll pass it around as needed
and just focus on shooting...
Huh?!
Already?!
Nice!
That was awesome!
For real?
Incredible!
That was so cool!
One more goal!
Run! Run!
You've got this!
That little...
A three-pointer?! No way!
Nice!
Nice one, Nekozaki!
Wow...
It doesn't even seem like a girls' game.
H-How did this even happen?
They're taking this too seriously!
She doesn't know the difference at all.
What's her deal? This is a first...
I've never met a girl like her before.
She's usually so cute, but right now...
She's unbelievably cool!
Good game. That was fun, huh?
Oh, Nekozaki-san.
Hey, Shikimori...
Let's have lunch together today!
Okay, sure.
That's really what happened?
You forgot about it?
Micchon has always hated
losing with a passion.
Oh, come on...
It's not that I hate losing...
Yeah, uh-huh.
Okay, let's find a swimsuit
that looks good on you!
Huh?
Hmm... Are we supposed to
write all of this out?
Which one?
(1) When the sum equals 9  (2) When the product equals 8
(3) The outcome of each roll is greater than the previous
26. Two dice are rolled three times. Write the number of outcomes
that produce the following results.
(1) 4 or 6  (2) A multiple of 4  (3) Less than 15
27. Write how many resulting terms are possible when each
of the following expressions is expanded.
Oh, you can just write the
tree diagram that fits.
Huh...
That's it. I knew you'd get it, Inuzuka-kun.
That's not too encouraging
coming from you...
Oh, finally, there they are.
Took you long enough!
I'll go get another chair.
Whoa, you're actually studying.
Yeah, because it's finals week.
Such a serious student.
I'm not gonna share my notes!
Boo...
Here, Hachimitsu-san.
Thanks.
Say, Shikimori-san...
You look kinda happy. What'd you buy?
Dang, he's sharp!
Dude, she obviously bought a swimsuit.
What are you talking about?
I-I didn't buy anything.
You're lying.
Whenever you lie,
it's written all over your face.
What is it? I'm curious!
I-I'm telling you, I didn't buy anything!
I mean it! I just did a little browsing.
Micchon laughing and then getting
mad is so fun to watch.
So no, I didn't buy anything.
Is it possible... that Micchon is
the one in the palm of his hand?
Well...
I guess there's no winning against
your own inner nature.
That sounds like another
disastrous experience.
I haven't been through one
that bad in a while.
I'd believe it.
I can't believe all of my writing
utensils broke on the same day!
But at least the teacher saw you needed
help before the exam ended, right?
Though it took fifteen minutes to
find another pen you could use...
Well, see you tomorrow.
Bye-bye.
L-Let's do our best tomorrow, too!
Dictionary of Archaic Japanese
5th Edition: Revised and Expanded
I need to get ready for the next round
of exams tomorrow, but I just can't!
That scared me. The volume's up to max...
Shikimori-san
Shikimori-san?
Hello, Ijumi here.
I know.
What has you calling so late at night?
They're Both Very Healthy Kids
Well... I thought you might be
buried in your blankets about now.
She
knows
I-I'm not!
You're not still feeling down, are you?
I-I'm fine now.
I'm glad to hear it.
Although, I actually called
for a different reason...
I just wanted to hear your voice.
I wish I could've seen her face just now!
Well, then shall we talk about something?
Sure.
Uh, let's see...
Oh!
Shikimori-san, can you see
the sky from your room?
The sky? Yes.
Can you see the North Star
in the northern sky?
The northern sky...
I see it!
Isn't it pretty?
Yes.
The North Star is part of the
constellation Ursa Minor,
and it's visible in the
northern sky year-round.
Oh, and the constellation shaped
like a W below that is Cassiopeia.
It's visible year-round, too.
Do you like stars, Izumi-san?
Yeah. I loved our class on constellations
in elementary school.
But every time my dad
took me out stargazing,
Star Chart
it always rained...
So I never got to see any
real constellations.
My luck is the worst.
Let's go!
Huh?
I'll take you somewhere you
can see a sky full of stars!
Shikimori-san...
In that case, I want to take you
someplace you want to go, too.
Huh? Why?
Why? Well, obviously...
Because I want to see you with
a happy look on your face.
You made sure we're going to the river
instead of the beach this summer for my sake.
So instead of somewhere I want to go,
I want to take you where you want to go.
I...
I can't think of anything at all...
Does that mean there's nowhere
she wants to go with me?!
I think it's just because I want
to go wherever you're going.
Whether it's the movies,
an amusement park, or the local park...
As long as I'm with you, anywhere is fine.
When I see you having fun,
it's fun for me, too.
So keep going wherever
you want to go, okay?
And take me along with you.
I love her!
Well, shall we go to sleep now?
It's getting late.
Oh...
You're right.
Thanks, Shikimori-san.
No, I should thank you.
You're amazing, you know?
Huh?
For some reason, I feel a lot better now.
I wish I could see you right now.
Shikimori-san?
I'm sorry... I'm very tired,
so I'm going to sleep now.
Goodnight!
Wha—
Shikimori-san
Call Ended 1:02.05
Oh, she hung up...
I-I didn't know she was so tired.
That was rude of me.
Okay! I'm gonna do my best
on tomorrow's exams, too!
Yeah!
Yuu, don't yell in the middle of the night.
Izumi-san
Call Ended 1:02.05
I wish I could've seen
his face when he said that...
Oh, my god!
I mean, obviously I want
to see him, too! Jeez!
It's the middle of the night.
Keep it down, would you?
Argh!
Are you listening?!
SEE YOU~
Beginners welcome!
Classroom
Easy Meat and Potato Stew
Ingredients (serves 2)
Potatoes
Onions
Shirataki noodles
Carrots
Beef
Hello, everyone.
Hello!
We're going to try making a meat dish today.
Let's start by preparing the vegetables.
You don't need to be so nervous, Mii-chan.
R-R-Right!
Okay, everyone, please begin.
Okay!
Let's make something tasty
and surprise Yuu, Mii-chan.
Yes!
Let's see. These are...
Oops.
Motoko-san!
Dear me.
Why would you pick it up that way?
Oh, that won't do, Mii-chan.
When you pull the knife toward you...
Like this. Apply more strength on the pull.
O-Okay...
I-I-I get it!
Wh-What are you doing?!
I was trying to get you to relax.
You're all red. How adorable.
A-Anyone would turn red after you...
It seems like you have a hard
time cutting with this.
She moves at her own pace!
Oh! Maybe it's a right-handed knife!
I'll ask if they have any left-handed ones!
I still get so nervous
when I'm alone with her.
But she invited me along,
so I'll do my best to cook.
Mii-chan!
They had one!
Thank you!
Ah...
You're not hurt, are you?
What about you? Are you all right?
Fair question...
Please be more careful when handling knives!